<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Discover Destinations</title>
	<atom:link href="https://discover-destinations.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://discover-destinations.com</link>
	<description>Discover Destinations provides the most competitive pricing with the highest quality product in the industry. We pass our wholesale rates on to our clients with a guarantee of 24 hour response time.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:35:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://discover-destinations.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Discover Destinations</title>
	<link>https://discover-destinations.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to sleep well on an international trip</title>
		<link>https://discover-destinations.com/how-to-sleep-well-on-an-international-trip/tips/</link>
					<comments>https://discover-destinations.com/how-to-sleep-well-on-an-international-trip/tips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://discover-destinations.com/?p=741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular" >
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
							<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner"><div class="blog-article-content-intro">

<span class="intro-bold">The lucky ones sleep like babies wherever they are in the world. But for many, good sleep is elusive, especially while traveling. New time zones, different beds, unaccustomed noises and unusual foods can lead to restless nights and daytime grogginess.</span>

</div>
<div class="blog-article-content-readmore">

A sound night’s sleep is even more important when traveling than it is at home. You’ve invested time and money in making the trip. There are sights to see, experiences to enjoy, and memories to make. Follow these six strategies, and you can increase your chances of sleeping well and being fresh the next day.
<h2>You may have to write off the first night</h2>
Have you heard of the “first night effect?” This well-documented phenomena is what often happens during the first night in a new place. It can take you longer to fall asleep and you may sleep less deeply and wake up more often than usual. According to a 2016 study published in Current Biology, this may be because, in a new place, one side of the brain remains alert to potential danger. Bottom line: Don’t be surprised if your first night isn’t the best. Plan to have better sleep on your second night.
<h2>Follow proven jet lag strategies</h2>
Traveling across multiple time zones can lead to jet lag, which can cause headaches, insomnia and irritability. According to the National Sleep Foundation, the best way to adjust to a new time zone is to get some sunshine. If you travel east, take in the morning sun. If traveling west, go for a walk in the late day sun. The point is to use the sun’s rays to readjust your body clock. On arrival day, avoid napping if possible and try to stay up until 10 pm local time for your best chance at adjusting quickly.
<h2>Ask about bedding and temperature</h2>
When booking lodging, ask about sleep-friendly amenities. Bedding can make a big difference. If you are accustomed to sleeping with a soft pillow or more than one pillow, find out what will be available in your room and ask for what you need. Room temperature also is critical to a good night’s sleep, and you may not have control over this. Make sure there will be extra blankets in an air-conditioned room, or a good fan in a room without cooling.
<h2>Pack a sleep kit</h2>
Room location can mean more or less ambient noise. If you’re in a hotel room right next to the elevator or the ice machine, sleep may be hard to come by. When choosing lodging, ask about the room’s location. Is it on the beach side or the street side? Ear plugs and an eye mask take up almost no room in your luggage, and can save you from restless hours of tossing and muttering.
<h2>Reserve hearty eating for the midday meal</h2>
Rich foods sit heavy on the digestion, making it harder to sleep. It’s best to eat heavy meals earlier in the day, giving your body more time to process the food before bedtime. What you drink during the day also can affect your sleep. Caffeinated beverages, including coffee, tea and cola, are stimulating. According to the National Sleep Foundation, caffeine has a half-life of about six hours. This means that if you drink coffee at 4 pm, half of the caffeine will still be with you at 10 pm. Be advised.
<h2>Relax before lights out</h2>
If you have a sleep ritual at home, try to replicate it as much as possible while traveling. Reading, light stretching or a warm bath can signal your body and brain that it’s time to shut down. Computer work, TV-watching or other screen time all have the opposite effect, and can wire you up when you most want to wind down.

As with all things, good sleep is often the result of a daily dose of common sense. Regular exercise and a healthy diet during the day lay the foundation, shored up by a consistent sleep schedule and a relaxing bedtime routine.

</div></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->		
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->	
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section -->
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://discover-destinations.com/how-to-sleep-well-on-an-international-trip/tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 packing hacks for international travel</title>
		<link>https://discover-destinations.com/top-10-packing-hacks-for-international-travel/tips/</link>
					<comments>https://discover-destinations.com/top-10-packing-hacks-for-international-travel/tips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://discover-destinations.com/?p=739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_section_regular" >
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_1  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner"><div class="blog-article-content-intro">

<strong>What you’ll need to pack for an international trip will depend on where you’re going and whether or not you’re traveling solo or with others. But whatever you bring, making sure it is lightweight, organized and consistently easy to repack as you move from place to place is critical. These ten tried-and-true travel-packing tips can help.</strong>

</div>
<div class="blog-article-content-readmore">
<h2><strong>Pack for the expected weather</strong></h2>
Romantic dreams of Paris can be foiled if your visit coincides with rainy season or chilly nights. Do a web search for average temperature highs and lows at your destination during the time you will be there, and choose clothing and accessories accordingly.
<h2><strong>Make lists – one per traveler</strong></h2>
The more travelers in your family, the more you need lists. But even solo travelers will benefit from thorough list-making before packing day. On your cellphone, create one list for each traveler. Then add to it over the course of a few weeks. This is a good way to note things each person uses daily or weekly so you don’t forget anything important.
<h2><strong>Roll your clothes</strong></h2>
Most of us fold, while we really should roll. Clothing that is rolled takes up less space, and emerges less wrinkled after many hours smashed into a suitcase.
<h2><strong>Fill your socks and use a shower cap</strong></h2>
Put your socks to work as protectors for breakables. Seal them in locking sandwich bags, and stuff them into your shoes for extra protection. And about those shoes – two pair per person, plus flip-flops is all you need. Use the hotel shower caps to cover the dirty soles of shoes for the trip home.
<h2><strong>Bag it up</strong></h2>
Organize clothing and other items in packing cubes, which are genius. Available from many retailers, they come in colors so you can color-code by traveler or by item category. They also make excellent holders for dirty laundry coming home. And, clear plastic zip-lock bags work miracles. Use sandwich-sized bags to hold toiletries, jewelry, power cords or small toys. Pack important paperwork, like copies of passports, credit-card company information, and travel medical insurance details flat in clear freezer bags.
<h2><strong>Keep shirt collars and bras in shape</strong></h2>
Roll a belt so it fits inside a shirt collar to maintain the collar’s shape. Stack bras, fold them in half, and then stuff the cup with socks or underwear to prevent flattening.
<h2><strong>Put the heavy stuff by the wheels</strong></h2>
Remember that your careful packing all shifts once you stand your suitcase up to roll it. Pack heavier items by the wheels so they stay put.
<h2><strong>Bring an empty canvas tote</strong></h2>
Don’t expect to find free bags at grocery stores or street markets in other countries. A heavy-duty canvas tote packs flat for the trip over, and will come in extremely handy while touring. Your tote can travel as a carry-on for the home leg of the trip, filled with your shopping treasures.
<h2><strong>Bring a power strip so you only need one converter</strong></h2>
The more travelers in your family, the more devices you have and the more charging equipment you need. To avoid having to invest in multiple power converters so you can plug in to the local electrical service, bring a multi-socket power strip that includes USB ports. That way, you need only one power converter, and can get by if there is only one outlet in your rental lodging.
<h2><strong>Include a few things you don’t think you need, but will come in handy</strong></h2>
So, you’ve made lists, rolled and packed, and you’re all set. Time to throw in some low-bulk extras you probably won’t think about ahead of time, but can be really helpful on your trip. Include a new deck of cards, a thermometer, a bungee cord, extra plastic bags in different sizes, instant coffee or cocoa, a plastic spoon, masking or painter’s tape, and a small flashlight.

Bon voyage!

</div></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section -->
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://discover-destinations.com/top-10-packing-hacks-for-international-travel/tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Healthy eating at the airport</title>
		<link>https://discover-destinations.com/healthy-eating-at-the-airport/tips/</link>
					<comments>https://discover-destinations.com/healthy-eating-at-the-airport/tips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://discover-destinations.com/?p=743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_2 et_section_regular" >
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_2">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_2  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_2  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner"><div class="blog-article-content-intro">

<span class="intro-bold">One of the little-thought-about aspects of international travel is the amount of time one spends at the airport. Between early airport arrival to allow time for security checks and layovers at stops along the way to your eventual destination, you can spend almost as much time in airports as you do on the plane.</span>

</div>
<div class="blog-article-content-readmore">

Accept the fact that you’ll be hungry during one of those airport hours. And, since what you eat at the airport can affect how you feel later, it’s important to make good choices. Follow these six tips to arrive at your destination feeling ready to conquer your next adventure.
<h2>Know what your airline offers</h2>
Start by knowing exactly how much and how often you will be fed on the plane. Most airlines will serve at least one full meal and one snack on overseas flights. But for some trips, you may start with a domestic leg and then perhaps a connecting flight somewhere along the way. Knowing when you can expect to eat on the plane can help you decide whether you need to augment with airport offerings along the way.
<h2>Do some terminal research ahead of time</h2>
Many larger airports publish a list of their restaurants online, some with menus. It’s worth checking them out before you leave to see what the food options might be in your particular terminal. Even if the menus aren’t in English, accompanying photos can give you a sense of the variety you might find. For smaller airports, options may be limited, so plan accordingly by bringing some food of your own.
<h2>Skip the typical fast food choices</h2>
You’ll be sitting for many hours, so who needs the extra calories? Plus, many fast food options are high in salt, which can cause fluid retention and swelling in your ankles and feet. If you do choose a fast food restaurant, opt for the healthier menu choices like grilled chicken wraps, salads or fruit and yogurt.
<h2>Eat like you would at home</h2>
Chances are, if you were home, you wouldn’t be loading up on giant pastries, burgers and fries. And, changing your diet radically at the start of a long journey can leave you feeling uncomfortable, sleepy or constipated once you arrive. Choose foods that are most like what you would typically eat at home to avoid shocking your digestive system at the time you most want it to behave.
<h2>Order smart at a restaurant</h2>
Restaurant portions can be huge and expensive, but there’s no reason to go big. At a sit-down restaurant, the appetizer and side dish menus often hide the healthiest options, and they are also less expensive. Look for dishes that contain a balance of protein, carbohydrates and fiber. For breakfast, whole grain oatmeal will leave you feeling satisfied for hours. Good choices for lunch or dinnertime might include a brothy vegetable or chicken soup, a grilled chicken salad, or a burrito bowl that includes beans or chicken (protein), greens (Vitamin C and fiber), and guacamole (healthy fat).
<h2>Stock up on healthy snacks for later</h2>
Wander through the airport, and you will probably be able to find quite a few options for good snacks you can eat later on the plane or during a layover in a small airport that has nothing but vending machines. Items that can hold for hours include a small cup of hummus, veggies to use as dippers, an apple, nuts or turkey jerky. Remember that foods containing protein – like hummus, nuts and jerky – can help you feel satisfied longer.

Even with the best set of ideas for healthy airport eating, having a good store of snacks from home is your best bet. Room in one’s carry-on is always in short supply, so pack snacks that count. Try nuts, dried fruit, popcorn, jerky, sunflower seeds, crackers and nut butter, and trail mix. And don’t eat them all in the first hour.

</div></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section -->
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://discover-destinations.com/healthy-eating-at-the-airport/tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
